A lot of the world's data lives in databases,
世界上许多数据都存储在数据库中
and most of the world's databases are accessed using structured query language,
而世界上绝大多数数据库都是通过结构化查询语言来访问的
which is typically abbreviated as as SQL, or SQL.
而结构化查询语言通常简称为 SQL 读作 /'es kju 'el/
It's been around since the 1970s,
该语言自 20 世纪 70 年代开始就有了
and is the most common method of accessing data and databases today.
如今 它已成为最常用的数据和数据库访问方式
SQL has a variety of functions that allow its users to read,
SQL 有各种各样的函数 能够让用户浏览、
manipulate, and change data.
操作和修改数据
It's also popular for data analysis for a few reasons.
它之所以在数据分析师中那么受欢迎 还有几个原因
First, it's semantically easy to understand and learn.
首先 这种语言的语义很容易理解和学习
It can be used to access large amounts of data directly where it's stored.
它能访问大量数据 而且是直接从数据存储位置访问
You don't have to copy data into other applications to view it,
要浏览数据 你不需要把数据复制到其它应用中
and you don't need to worry about your spreadsheet
也不需要担心数据超载
program crashing because of data overload.
会导致电子表格程序崩溃
It's easy to audit and replicate.
SQL 也易于审核和复制
In a spreadsheet tool like Excel,
在 Excel 等电子表格工具中
you have to click in to each cell to know how they're calculated.
你需要逐个点击单元格 才能知道每个单元格的计算方式
With SQL, you can just read a query from top to bottom, nothing's hidden.
用 SQL 你只需从头到尾看完一个查询 一切就无所遁形了
Finally, SQL can run queries on multiple tables at once, across large datasets.
最后 SQL 能够同时在多个表中运行查询 就算数据集很庞大也不怕
It's great for performing the types of aggregations you might
SQL 的统计也不错
normally do in an Excel pivot table, sums,
可能通常你是用 Excel 的数据透视表来做统计的
counts, minimums and maximums,
像是总和、计数、最小值和最大值等操作
etcetera, but Excel maxes out at just over 1 million rows.
但 Excel 最多只能容纳一百多万行
With SQL, you can query across billions of rows at a time.
而用 SQL 你一次可以查询数十亿行
Maybe most importantly, SQL's incredibly flexible,
最重要的一点或许是 SQL 特别灵活
especially when compared to out of the box dashboard products like Google Analytics.
尤其是与那些即用仪表板产品比较 如 Google Analytics
In Google Analytics, you might be able to answer questions like,
可能你能用 Google Analytics 来回答一些问题 如
which pages on my site receive the most traffic?
我的站点哪些页面流量最大？
And where does it come from?
这些流量从何而来？
But you can use SQL's filtering capabilities to answer much deeper,
但是用 SQL 的过滤功能 你能回答更深层次
more complex questions like,
更复杂的问题 如
how many viewers return to my site between one and three weeks after their first visit?
游客在首次访问我的站点后 有多少人会在一到三周内重返？
And what typically brings them back?
通常是什么吸引他们回来的？
These features make SQL one of
这些特征让 SQL
the primary data analysis tools for both beginners and experts.
成为初学者和专家的主要数据分析工具之一